<addon id="script.games.rom.collection.browser" name="Rom Collection Browser" provider-name="bruny, malte" version="2.3.0">
  <requires>
    
    <import addon="xbmc.addon" version="17.0.0" />
    
    <import addon="xbmc.python" version="3.0.0" />
    <import addon="service.rom.collection.browser" version="1.0.0" />
    
    <import addon="script.module.requests" version="2.18.4" />
  </requires>
  <extension library="default.py" point="xbmc.python.script">
    <provides>executable game</provides>
  </extension>
  <extension point="xbmc.addon.metadata">
    <news>2.3.0 (04/2020)
- change url to thegamesdb API
- remove legacy.thegamesdb.net scraper
    </news>
    <summary lang="be_BY">Import, browse and launch games in XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="ca_ES">Importa, cerca i arranca jocs en l'XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="da_DK">Importere, gennemse og starte spil i XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="de_DE">Importiert, verwaltet und startet Spiele in XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="el_GR">Εισαγάγετε, αναζητήστε και εκτελέστε παιχνίδια στο XBMC.</summary>
    <summary lang="en_GB">Import, browse and launch games in XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="en_NZ">Import, browse and launch games in XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="es_ES">Importa, explora y ejecuta juegos en XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="fr_FR">Importez, parcourez et lancez vos jeux depuis XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="fr_CA">Importer, parcourir et lancer des jeux dans XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="gl_ES">Importar, buscar e executar xogos no XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="hu_HU">Konzol játék ROM-ok böngészése</summary>
    <summary lang="id_ID">Impor, telusuri dan mainkan permainan di XMBC</summary>
    <summary lang="it_IT">Importa, sfoglia e lancia i giochi da XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="nl_NL">Importeer, doorzoek en start spellen in XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="pl_PL">Importowanie, przeglądanie i uruchamianie gier w XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="pt_PT">Importe, navegue e execute jogos no XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="pt_BR">Importe, navegue e execute jogos no XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="ru_RU">Импорт, обзор и запуск игр в XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="sv_SE">Importera, bläddra och starta spel i XBMC</summary>
    <summary lang="zh_CN">在 XBMC 中导入、浏览和运行游戏</summary>
    <description lang="be_BY">With this Addon you can browse and launch emulator roms and standalone games in XBMC. See the wiki page for more information: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

First Use:
  * On first launch RCB will start a simple configuration wizard
  * After the wizard is completed RCB will ask you to import your games
  * If needed you can launch the wizard anytime via context menu
  * Just press "C" on your keyboard or "Menu" on your remote

Features:
  * scan your rom folders and import games to local database
  * scrape artwork and meta data from various online sources
  * import local available descriptions, artwork and videos
  * filter games by console, genre, year and publisher
  * favorites function
  * automatic video playback in video window
  * fullscreen video browser
  * game details page
  * dedicated MAME views to display cabinets and marquees
  * launch roms and standalone games in solo or non-solo mode
  * detect games in zip and 7z archives and ask user which game to load
  * direct launching of savestate files
  * ...
</description>
    <description lang="de_DE">Mit diesem Addon können Roms und PC-Spiele verwaltet und gestartet werden. Mehr Informationen im RCB wiki: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

Erste Schritte:
  * Beim ersten Aufruf startet RCB einen Konfigurations-Assistenten
  * Nach der Konfiguration importiert RCB die Spiele in seine Datenbank
  * Der Assistent kann auch jederzeit aus RCB heraus gestartet werden
  * Drücke dazu "C" auf der Tastatur oder "Menu" auf der Fernbedienung

Features:
  * Scannt Verzeichnisse rekursiv und importiert Spiele in die Datenbank
  * Liest Artwork und Metadaten aus verschiedenen Online-Quellen
  * Importiert lokal verfügbare Infos, Artwork und Videos
  * Filtert Spiele nach Konsole, Genre, Jahr und Herausgeber
  * Favoriten-Funktion
  * Automatisches Abspielen von Videos
  * Fullscreen Video Browser
  * Detailseite mit weiteren Spiele-Infos
  * spezielle MAME Sichten für Cabinets und Banner
  * Startet Spiele im Solo-Modus (beendet XBMC vor dem Start des Spiels)
  * Erkennt Spiele in zip und 7z Archiven
  * Savestates können direkt gestartet werden (Emulator-abhängig)
  * ...
</description>
    <description lang="el_GR">Με αυτό το Πρόσθετο μπορείτε να βρείτε και να παίξετε παιχνίδια εξομοιωτών (Rom) καθώς και αυτόνομα παιχνίδια στο XBMC. Δείτε τη σελίδα του wiki για περισσότερες πληροφορίες: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome

Πρώτη Χρήση:
  * Κατά την πρώτη εκτέλεση του RCB θα ξεκινήσει ένας οδηγός εγκατάστασης
  * Μετά την ολοκλήρωση του οδηγού το RCB θα σας ζητήσει να εισάγετε τα παιχνίδια σας
  * Αν χρειαστεί, μπορείτε να εκτελέσετε τον οδηγό ανά πάσα στιγμή από το μενού επιλογών
  * Απλά πιέστε το "C" στο πληκτρολόγιό σας ή το "Μενού" στο τηλεχειριστήριό σας

Χαρακτηριστικά:
  * σαρώστε τους φακέλους των rom σας και εισάγετε παιχνίδια στην τοπική βάση δεδομένων
  * λήψη εικόνων και μετα-δεδομένων μέσω της διαδικασίας του scrape από διάφορες διαδικτυακές πηγές
  * εισαγωγή διαθέσιμων τοπικών περιγραφών, εικόνων και βίντεο
  * φιλτράρισμα παιχνιδιών ανά παιχνιδομηχανή, είδος, έτος και εταιρεία
  * λειτουργία αγαπημένων
  * αυτόματη αναπαραγωγή βίντεο σε παράθυρο
  * προβολή βίντεο πλήρους οθόνης
  * σελίδα πληροφοριών παιχνιδιών
  * εξειδικευμένες προβολές MAME για εμφάνιση cabinet και marquee
  * έναρξη rom και παιχνιδιών σε λειτουργία solo και μη
  * εντοπισμός παιχνιδιών σε αρχεία zip και 7z και ερώτηση χρήστη σχετικά με το ποιο παιχνίδι να φορτωθεί
  * άμεση έναρξη των αποθηκευμένων αρχείων
  * ...
</description>
    <description lang="en_GB">With this Addon you can browse and launch emulator roms and standalone games in XBMC. See the wiki page for more information: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

First Use:
  * On first launch RCB will start a simple configuration wizard
  * After the wizard is completed RCB will ask you to import your games
  * If needed you can launch the wizard anytime via context menu
  * Just press "C" on your keyboard or "Menu" on your remote

Features:
  * scan your rom folders and import games to local database
  * scrape artwork and meta data from various online sources
  * import local available descriptions, artwork and videos
  * filter games by console, genre, year and publisher
  * favorites function
  * automatic video playback in video window
  * fullscreen video browser
  * game details page
  * dedicated MAME views to display cabinets and marquees
  * launch roms and standalone games in solo or non-solo mode
  * detect games in zip and 7z archives and ask user which game to load
  * direct launching of savestate files
  * ...
</description>
    <description lang="en_NZ">With this Addon you can browse and launch emulator roms and standalone games in XBMC. See the wiki page for more information: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

First Use:
  * On first launch RCB will start a simple configuration wizard
  * After the wizard is completed RCB will ask you to import your games
  * If needed you can launch the wizard anytime via context menu
  * Just press "C" on your keyboard or "Menu" on your remote

Features:
  * scan your rom folders and import games to local database
  * scrape artwork and meta data from various online sources
  * import local available descriptions, artwork and videos
  * filter games by console, genre, year and publisher
  * favourites function
  * automatic video playback in video window
  * fullscreen video browser
  * game details page
  * dedicated MAME views to display cabinets and marquees
  * launch roms and standalone games in solo or non-solo mode
  * detect games in zip and 7z archives and ask user which game to load
  * direct launching of savestate files
  * ...
</description>
    <description lang="es_ES">Con este complemento puedes explorar y ejecutar ROMs de emulador y juegos independientes en XBMC. Visita la página wiki para más información: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

Primer Uso:
  * Al ejecutarse por primera vez, RCB mostrará un sencillo asistente de configuración
  * Una vez completado el asistente, RCB te solicitará importar tus juegos
  * Si lo necesitas, puedes ejecutar el asistente en cualquier momento a través del menú contextual
  * Tan solo tienes que pulsar "C" en el teclado o "Menú" en el mando a distancia

Características:
  * escanea tus carpetas con ROMs e importa los juegos a una base de datos local
  * descarga imágenes y metadatos desde varias fuentes online
  * importa descripciones, imágenes y videos disponibles localmente
  * filtra los juegos por consola, género, año y editor
  * función de favoritos
  * reproducción automática de videos en ventana de video
  * navegador de videos a pantalla completa
  * página de detalles del juego
  * vistas de MAME dedicadas, mostrando máquinas y marcos
  * ejecuta ROMs y juegos independiente en modo solo o no-solo
  * detecta juegos en archivos zip y 7z y pregunta al usuario qué juego desea cargar
  * ejecución directa de archivos de partidas guardadas
  * ...
</description>
    <description lang="fr_FR">Avec cette extension, vous pouvez parcourir et lancer des roms d'émulateur ainsi que des jeux autonomes. Visitez le wiki pour plus d'informations : http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.
Première utilisation :
* Au premier démarrage RCB lancera un assistant de configuration simplifié.
* Une fois cette configuration terminée RCB vous proposera d'importer vos jeux.
* Au besoin, vous pouvez relancer l'assistant de configuration à tout moment depuis le menu contextuel.
* Appuyez sur la touche "C" de votre clavier ou sur "Menu" de votre télécommande.

Caractéristiques :
* Analyse votre dossier de roms et importe les jeux dans une base de données locale
* Récupère les illustrations et métadonnées depuis différentes sources en ligne
* Importe vos descriptifs, illustrations et vidéos stockés localement
* Filtre vos jeux par console, genre, année et éditeur
* Gestion des favoris
* lecture automatique des vidéos dans une fenêtre
* Navigation parmi les vidéos en plein écran
* Fiche de jeux détaillée
* Vues dédiées pour MAME affichant cabinets et marquees
* Lancement des roms et jeux en mode solo ou non
* Détecte les jeux dans les fichiers zip et 7z et demande à l'utilisateur quel jeux lancer
* lance directement une sauvegarde

</description>
    <description lang="fr_CA">Avec cet addiciel vous pouvez parcourir et lancer des roms d'émulateurs et des jeux autonomes dans XBMC. Consulter le wiki pour plus d'informations : http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

Première utilisation :
* au premier lancement RCB lancera un assistant simple de configuration
* un fois l'assistant terminé RCB vous demandera d'importer vos jeux
* au besoin vous pouvez lancer l'assistant à tout moment avec le menu contextuel
* pesez juste sur « C » sur votre clavier, ou « Menu » sur votre télécommande

Caractéristiques :
* balayer votre dossier de ROM et importer les jeux dans la base de données locale
* extraire les illustrations et les métadonnées de diverses sources en ligne
* importer les descriptions, les illustrations et les vidéos locales disponibles
* filtrer les jeux par console, genre, année et éditeur
* fonction favoris
* lecture vidéo automatique dans la fenêtre vidéo
* navigateur vidéo en plein écran
* page de détails des jeux
* vues MAME dédiées pour afficher les cabinets et les marquises
* lancer les ROM et les jeux autonomes en mode solo ou non
* détecter les jeux dans les archives zip et 7z et demander à l'utilisateur quel jeu charger
* lancement direct des fichiers de sauvegarde d'état
* ... 
</description>
    <description lang="hu_HU">Jelenlegi funkciók:
  * játékok szűrése konzoltípus, műfaj, év és kiadó alapján
  * rom-ok indítása külső emulátorral
  * a program beállítása egy xml fájl segítségével
  * egyszerű de testreszabható leírófájl-feldolgozó
  * játékonként különböző képek és videók megjelenítése
  * játéktartalom és kiegészítő információk megjelenítése
</description>
    <description lang="id_ID">Dengan Addon ini Anda dapat menelusuri dan menjalankan rom emulator dan program permainan di XBMC. Lihat halaman wiki untuk informasi lebih lanjut: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

Pemakaian Pertama:
* Saat pertama kali menjalankan RCB akan memulai penuntun konfigurasi sederhana
* Setelah tuntunan selesai RCB akan menanyakan Anda untuk mengimpor permainan
* Jika diperlukan Anda dapat menjalankan tuntunan kapan saja melalui menu konteks
* Tekan "C" pada papan ketik atau "Menu" pada remote Anda

Fitur:
* pindai folder rom Anda dan impor permainan ke basis data lokal
* salin karya seni dan meta data dari berbagai sumber daring
* impor deskripsi, karya seni dan video yang tersedia lokal
* filter permainan berdasarkan konsol, tema, tahun dan penerbit
* fungsi favorit
* pemaran video otomatis di jendela video
* Penelusuran video layar penuh
* halaman rincian permainan
* tampilan MAME dedikasi untuk menampilkan kabinet dan marquee
* deteksi permainan dalam arsip zip dan 7z serta menanyakan pengguna permainan mana yang akan dimuat
* menjalankan langsung dari berkas savestate
* ...
</description>
    <description lang="it_IT">Con questo addon puoi sfogliare e lanciare le rom degli emulatori o giochi standalone in XBMC. Consulta la pagina wiki per maggiori informazioni : http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

Prima uso:
  * Al primo avvio, RCB avvia una semplice procedura di configurazione
  * Al termine, RCB ti chiederà di importare i tuoi giochi
  * Se necessario, puoi avviare la procedura di configurazione in qualsiasi momento tramite il menu contestuale
  * Premi semplicemente "C" sulla tua tastiera o il tasto "Menu" del tuo telecomando

Caratteristiche:
  * Scansiona le tue cartelle contenenti rom e importa i giochi in un database locale
  * Esegui lo scraping degli artwork e dei metadati da varie sorgenti online
  * Importa descrizioni, artwork e video già disponibili in locale
  * Filtra i giochi per console, genere, anno e editore
  * Funzione preferiti 
  * Esecuzione automatica dei video nella finestra video
  * Sfoglia video a schermo intero
  * Pagina dettagli del gioco
  * Viste specifiche per MAME per visualizzare i cabinet e i marquee
  * Lancia rom e giochi standalone in modalità "Solo" e "Non solo"
  * Rileva giochi in archivi .zip e .7z, e chiede all'utente quale gioco eseguire
  * Lancio diretto da file di salvataggio del gioco
  * ...
</description>
    <description lang="nl_NL">Met deze Add-on kan je zoeken en starten van emulator roms en alleenstaande Spellen in XBMC. Zie de wikipagina voor meer informatie:
http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

Bij eerste keer:
* Bij de eerste keer Starten zal RCB een gemakkelijke configuratie wizard starten
* Nadat de wizard gereed is zal RCB jou vragen jouw spellen te importeren
* wanneer nodig kan je de wizard elke keer starten via het context menu
* Druk alleen "C" op je toetsenbord of "menu"op jouw afstandsbediening

Functies:
* Scan jouw rom folders en importeer spellen naar jou lokale database
* scrape Artwork en Meta data van uit verschillende online bronnen
* importeer lokaal beschikbare omschrijvingen, artwork en video`s
* Filter spellen op Console, genre, jaar en uitgever
* Favorieten functie
* Automatisch film terugspelen optie in videoscherm
* Volledig scherm Video browser
* Spel details pagina
* Toegewijde MAME weergaven om Cabinets en marquees*
* Start Roms en Alleenstaande spellen in Solo of niet-solo modus
* detecteer spellen in zip en 7z archieven en vraag gebruiker welk spel te laden
* direct starten van opgeslagen bestanden
* ...

</description>
    <description lang="pt_PT">Com este Addon pode navegar e jogar roms de emuladores e jogos individuais no seu XBMC. Veja a página de wiki para mais informação: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

Primeiro uso:
  * Na primeira execução, RCB iniciará um assistente de configuração
  * Após a configuraçã estar completa, o RCB irá importar os seus jogos
  * Se precisar, pode iniciar o assistente através do menu de contexto
  * Basta premir "C" no seu teclado ou "Menu" no seu remoto

Funcionalidades:
  * analisar as suas pastas de roms e importar jogos para a base de dados local
  * obter artwork e metadados de várias fontes online
  * importar descrições, artwork e vídeos disponíveis localmente
  * filtrar jogos por consola, género, ano e editora
  * função de favoritos
  * reprodução de vídeo automática na janela de vídeo
  * navegador de vídeos em ecrã cheio
  * página de detalhes do jogo
  * vistas especiais de MAME para exibir cabinets e marquees
  * iniciar roms e jogos autónomos em modo solo ou não-solo
  * detectar jogos em ficheiros zip e 7z e perguntar ao utilizador qual é o jogo a iniciar
  * iniciar directamente ficheiros de savestate
  * ...
</description>
    <description lang="pt_BR">Com esse addon você pode navegar e lançar roms de emuladores e jogos através do xbmc. Veja a pagina de wiki para mais informações:
http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.(\n)(\n)
Primeiro Uso:
 No primeiro lançamento o RCB irá iniciar um assistente de configuração simples(
*Depois de concluir o assistente RCB irá pedir para importar seus jogos
*Se necessário, você pode iniciar o assistente a qualquer momento através do menu de contexto
* Basta pressionar "C" no seu teclado ou "Menu" em seu controle remoto

Características:
* varredura de suas pastas com roms e importação de jogos para um banco de dados local
* procura arte e meta-dados de várias fontes on-line
* importação local para descrições e obras de arte e vídeos se disponíveis
* filtrar jogos por console, gênero, ano e editor
* função favoritos
* reprodução automática de videos na janela do navegador(\n)
*vídeo em tela cheia no navegador
* pagina de detalhes do jogo
* vistas dedicadas a MAME para exibir cabines e letreiros(\n)
* lançamento de roms e jogos independentes no modo sozinho ou não sozinho
* detectar jogos em arquivos ZIP e 7z e perguntar ao usuário qual jogo carregar
* lançamento direto de arquivos de savestate
.
</description>
    <description lang="ru_RU">С помощью этого дополнения можно просматривать и запускать ROM эмуляторы и игры XBMC. Дополнительную информацию можно увидеть на странице Wiki по адресу: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

Первый запуск:
  * При первом запуске RCB будет запущен простой мастер конфигураций
  * После завершения мастера RCB спросит Вас, какие игры импортировать
  * Если нужно, вы можете запустить мастер повторно в контекстном меню
  * Нажмите "C" на клавиатуре или "Menu" на пульте управления

Возможности:
  * Сканирование папок с образами игр и добавление их в вашу базу данных
  * Искать обложки и мета данные  с различных онлайн источников
  * загружать доступные локальные описания, обложки и видео
  * фильтровать игры по типу консоли, жанру, году, издателю
  * избранное
  * автоматическое воспроизведение видео в окне
  * полноэкранный видео браузер
  * страница описаний игр
  * dedicated MAME views to display cabinets and marquees
  * Запускать образы и игры в одно и многопользовательском режимах
  * определять игры в архивах zip и 7z и затем спрашивать пользователя, что загружать
  * Прямой запуск по файлам сохранений
  * ...
</description>
    <description lang="sv_SE">Med detta tillägg kan du bläddra och starta emulatorbaserade ROMS och spel i XBMC.
Se wiki för mer information: http://code.google.com/p/romcollectionbrowser/wiki/Welcome.

Första start:
  * Vid första start kommer RCB starta en enkel inställningsguide
  * När guiden är klar kommer RCB be dig importera dina spel
  * Om du behöver, kan du starta guiden när som helst via undermenyn
  * Tryck "C" på ditt tangentbord eller "Meny" på din fjärrkontroll

Egenskaper:
  * sök igenom mappar med roms och importera spel till lokal databas
  * skrapa bilder och metadata från olika onlinekällor
  * importera lokala beskrivningar, bilder och filmer
  * filtrera spel efter konsol, genre, år och utgivare
  * favoriter
  * automatisk filmuppspelning i videofönster
  * fullskärmsbläddrare för film
  * sida med detaljerad spelinformation
  * dedikerade MAME-vyer för att visa spelkabinett
  * starta roms och spel i solo eller non-solo läge
  * hitta spel i zip och 7z arkiv och fråga användaren vilket spel att ladda
  * direktstart av savestate fier
  * ...
</description>
    <language />
    <platform>android freebsd ios linux osx windows</platform>
    <license>GNU GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE. Version 2, June 1991</license>
    <forum>forum.kodi.tv/showthread.php?tid=70115</forum>
    <website>https://github.com/maloep/romcollectionbrowser</website>
    <source>https://github.com/maloep/romcollectionbrowser</source>
    <assets>
      <icon>icon.png</icon>
    </assets>
  </extension>
</addon>