<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<response><error><![CDATA[OK]]></error><limit>20</limit><number_of_page_results>2</number_of_page_results><number_of_total_results>2</number_of_total_results><offset>0</offset><results><game><aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases><api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.giantbomb.com/game/17123/]]></api_detail_url><date_added>2008-04-01 16:31:55</date_added><date_last_updated>2010-08-09 13:47:01.650392</date_last_updated><deck><![CDATA[ActRaiser 2 is the sequel to the game ActRaiser. ActRaiser 2 is more focused on action than its predecessor.]]></deck><description><![CDATA[<h2>Story</h2><br />There is some discussion as to when this entry takes place in the Actraiser time line. The opening intro sequence seems to be a retelling of the very end of the original Actraiser, using the newer character sprite for The Master but the older sprite for series antagonist Tanzra. This would place Actraiser 2 chronologicaly after the first game. <br /><br />As the game opens, your servant angels inform you that the evil Tanzra has been awoken by his evil minions, who have manifested as representations of the classical seven deadly sins: Greed, Sloth, Envy, Wrath, Pride, Lust and Gluttony. These minions have overtaken the land and it is your duty to rid the world of this evil yet again.<br /><br />During the game's end credits, it is declared that "The Master will live  forever", followed by an image of the statue of The Master slowly  eroding over time. The statue's sword and right wing fall off,  suggesting the growth of civilization and the increase of mankind's  self-sufficiency. This reflects the ending of the original <i>ActRaiser</i>, where the servant speculates that someday the world may be so independent that it will forget about the Master.<br /><br /><h2>Gameplay</h2><b><u><br /></u></b>While the first Actraiser<b><u> </u></b>split levels into sim-like stages and pure Rastan style action stages, Actraiser 2 forgoes the sim elements for pure action. The overworld is still present for you to get from land to land with your helper angel returning to breif you on the situation for each town (This setup would be seen in much later but in a very similar fashion in Valkery Profile)<br /><br />Once on land, God would fight his way through the possesed and cursed towns eventually defeting the minnion controlling it, thus returning it back to normal.<br /><br />While the game is stil a traditional side scrolling action title, two key changes were made. One was the addition of a shield for a slightly more tactical approach similar to Zelda 2. The other addition was that of wings which could be used to reach new heights, glide over distances and put the player in position to do devestating arial moves.<br /><br /><b><u>Allusions to Other Media<br /><br /></u></b>There are many elements in the game which act as allusions to classical literature, myth and religion. Each of the bosses, for example, are a manifestation of the seven deadly sins. <br /><br />Some of the stages in the game are meant to be ironic regarding the  blighting nature of Tanzra's demons. The townsmen in the city of Leon  are sent to the underground prison of Gratis for not paying their taxes  by a newly appointed king named Kolunikus who is afflicted by Greed.  The final staged level of the game pits the player against a  mechanically engineered god in the city of Humbleton, a battle of Pride (a satire on the Biblical story of the Tower of Babel).<br /><br />After the player slays the first six deadly sins, the Tower Of Babel appears in which you fight the final sin, Pride. You then descend into Hell  where you again fight the seven sins as well as Tanzra himself, a beast  frozen waist-deep in a lake of ice (just as Satan was in the <i>Inferno</i> in <i>The Divine Comedy</i>).<br /><br /><u><b>Reception<br /></b></u>The game sold about 180,000 copies worldwide, with 40,000 copies sold  in Japan and Europe respectively and 100,000 sold in the USA.<br /><br /><br /><b><u><br /></u></b>]]></description><expected_release_month>11</expected_release_month><expected_release_quarter></expected_release_quarter><expected_release_year>1993</expected_release_year><id>17123</id><image><icon_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/7464/637098-604318_icon.jpg]]></icon_url><medium_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/7464/637098-604318_small.jpg]]></medium_url><screen_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/7464/637098-604318_screen.jpg]]></screen_url><small_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/7464/637098-604318_small.jpg]]></small_url><super_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/7464/637098-604318_super.jpg]]></super_url><thumb_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/7464/637098-604318_thumb.jpg]]></thumb_url><tiny_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/7464/637098-604318_tiny.jpg]]></tiny_url></image><name><![CDATA[ActRaiser 2]]></name><number_of_user_reviews>0</number_of_user_reviews><original_game_rating></original_game_rating><original_release_date></original_release_date><resource_type><![CDATA[game]]></resource_type><site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.giantbomb.com/actraiser-2/61-17123/]]></site_detail_url></game><game><aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases><api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.giantbomb.com/game/7274/]]></api_detail_url><date_added>2008-04-01 15:41:27</date_added><date_last_updated>2010-09-27 02:39:08.630934</date_last_updated><deck><![CDATA[ActRaiser is a unique hybrid of two genres; city-building and action platformer. The player takes control of the powerful entity known as the Master in his quest to rebuild civilization.]]></deck><description><![CDATA[<h2>Overview<div class="js-item-cage" rel="image" title="image" id="464818"><div class="wiki-img-right"><div class="wiki-img-thumb"><a href="http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/6150/464818-title_super.gif" title="The title screen of the Super Nintendo version"><img id="464818" src="http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/6150/464818-title_thumb.gif" alt="The title screen of the Super Nintendo version" /></a><div class="item-caption p-4">The title screen of the Super Nintendo version</div></div></div></div></h2>ActRaiser is a Super Nintendo Entertainment System city-building simulation and action hybrid. The game was developed by <a href="/quintet-co-ltd/65-3151/">Quintet</a> and published by <a href="/enix/65-6337/">Enix</a> (before their merge with <a href="/square-company-ltd/65-6323/">Square</a>), and the game was released during November of 1991. Although there was a sequel for the game, <a href="/actraiser-2/61-17123/">ActRaiser 2</a>, it completely abandoned the simulation aspects of the original, which caused many fans to dislike it.<br /><br />ActRaiser was also released in 2007 on the Wii Virtual Console in Europe, North America, and Japan. European mobile phones got a version of the game with a 2004 release as well. The game was also part of the Nintendo Super System, an arcade system that allowed gamers to preview upcoming releases.<br /><br />ActRaiser is a relatively well-received game. It was accepted into GameSpot's <a href="http://www.gamespot.com/gamespot/features/all/greatestgames/p-30.html" rel="nofollow">Greats Games of All Time</a> in 2003 and was rated the 150th best game on a Nintendo system by Nintendo Power.<br /><br /><h2>Plot</h2>Not much of a plot exists in the actual game itself in ActRaiser. However, much is explained via the instruction booklet. The instruction booklet states that <a href="/tanzra/94-1239/">Tanzra</a> and his six guardians attacked the Master. The Master was injured after the long battle, so he retreated to his sky palace and proceeded to fall into a deep sleep.<br /><br />While the Master was sleeping, Tanzra drove the world into ruins. He divided the world into six lands with each being ruled by one of the guardians. When the Master awakes, fully rejuvenated, he is ready to free the world from the oppression of Tanzra.<br /><br />After defeating Tanzra, civilizations begin to stop worshiping the Master with many losing faith in him and turning to other things. The servant notes this, and says that people only appear to pray and trust to the Master in times of trouble.<br /><br /><h2>Gameplay</h2>The gameplay of ActRaiser has constantly been called unique, innovative, and such other adjectives. The player takes control of an incredibly powerful being known only as the Master. The Master has been awakened from a deep sleep to find the world in ruin. He and his loyal servant (a small angelic creature) then set out to rebuild civilization.<br /><br /><div class="js-item-cage" rel="image" title="image" id="389799"><div class="wiki-img-left"><div class="wiki-img-thumb"><a href="http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/2014/389799-actraiser_58_super.png" title="The Master takes the form of a warrior; here he is battling a boss"><img id="389799" src="http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/2014/389799-actraiser_58_thumb.png" alt="The Master takes the form of a warrior; here he is battling a boss" /></a><div class="item-caption p-4">The Master takes the form of a warrior; here he is battling a boss</div></div></div></div>To begin this rebuilding process, the Master positions his sky palace above an area filled with enemies and demons. Then, the Master takes on the form of a strong warrior wielding a large sword. In these side-scrolling areas, the warrior uses his sword to dispatch many hazards, such as environmental hazards or monsters. The warrior can pick up power-ups by destroying statues situated in certain places around the level. The power-ups have a variety of effects, from healing the warrior, to bonus points. After defeating the boss of the level, the warrior moves onto the next section of the city-building portion.<br /><br />The life bar that the Master has in his warrior form can also be extended as the Master gains levels. Leveling up is done through an experience system, in which the combined population of the Master's rebuilt towns amasses into experience. Also gained in leveling up is more SP, which can then be used to preform miraculous events in the city-building part of the game. Magical spells can also be granted to the Master through his followers that he can use in his warrior form. These spells deal significantly more damage than regular attacks, making them essential to the completion of the game.<br /><br />In the city-building portion of the game, the player takes control of the Master's servant; a small angelic creature, likely a cupid. Each town begins with only two humans, who then follow the Master's commands and aid him in rebuilding his world. They must be guided (the direction they are guided in is where they will build), and in turn will build houses, roads, and farms. The villagers eventually gain use of other skills, such as composing music or creating bridges.<div class="js-item-cage" rel="image" title="image" id="464816"><div class="wiki-img-right"><div class="wiki-img-thumb"><a href="http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/6150/464816-oversee_super.gif" title="Building a city"><img id="464816" src="http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/6150/464816-oversee_thumb.gif" alt="Building a city" /></a><div class="item-caption p-4">Building a city</div></div></div></div><br />The Master also has the use of several magical powers in the city-building portion. He can summon lightning, rain, sun, wind, or earthquakes. Using these abilities, trees, rocks, snow, monsters, and much more can be cleared. In a few sections of the game, the abilities must be used to assist the villagers, starting windmills or putting out fires, for example.<br /><br />However, the city-building isn't calm. There are several Monster Lairs scattered around the map. Monsters are spawned out of these lairs. The people have the ability to seal these lairs, making it a necessity to guide the population to the lairs. The cupid can attack the monsters using his arrows, but once he loses all of his life, he cannot attack until the people increase in population. Once all of the Monster Lairs are sealed, the people can gain even more advanced technology and techniques.]]></description><expected_release_month>12</expected_release_month><expected_release_quarter>4</expected_release_quarter><expected_release_year>1991</expected_release_year><id>7274</id><image><icon_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/461/177175-563502_29060_front_icon.jpg]]></icon_url><medium_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/461/177175-563502_29060_front_small.jpg]]></medium_url><screen_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/461/177175-563502_29060_front_screen.jpg]]></screen_url><small_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/461/177175-563502_29060_front_small.jpg]]></small_url><super_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/461/177175-563502_29060_front_super.jpg]]></super_url><thumb_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/461/177175-563502_29060_front_thumb.jpg]]></thumb_url><tiny_url><![CDATA[http://media.giantbomb.com/uploads/0/461/177175-563502_29060_front_tiny.jpg]]></tiny_url></image><name><![CDATA[ActRaiser]]></name><number_of_user_reviews>4</number_of_user_reviews><original_game_rating></original_game_rating><original_release_date>1990-12-15 00:00:00</original_release_date><resource_type><![CDATA[game]]></resource_type><site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.giantbomb.com/actraiser/61-7274/]]></site_detail_url></game></results><status_code>1</status_code></response>